# **Leland Jordon**

Web Developer - USMC - B.A. - TS Clearance

202-425-7694

lelandjordon@mac.com

Washington, DC

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lelandjordon

https://lelandjordon.github.io/index.html

#### **Profile**

I've been described as a steadfast team leader, motivating others with inventive ways to solve problems. My music and military experiences taught me the value of being a good team member and a respected manager, helping organizations to achieve their goals.

#### Technical Skills/Certifications

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Ruby on Rails, MEAN stack, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, SQL, Git, Subversion, Sitecore CMS, Microsoft and Apple office software, Top Secret clearance (Apr 2018), Security+ (Aug 2018)

### **Projects**

http://lelandjordon.github.io/pet-seeker/ – My final class project, combining an AngularJS front-end app with a custom Rails API as a fictional animal shelter website.

https://blog.angelhack.com/2016/06/02/code4impact-911beacon – Awarded the Code 4 Impact award at AngelHack DC 2016, this project would have used a mobile app to send data to local emergency response centers.

## **Professional Experience**

#### APP DEVELOPER, HYBRID DATA SECURITY, FBI; WASHINGTON, DC

2019-2019

Assisted in developing in-house application for creating and managing SCI access requests.

- $\bullet \ \ \, \text{Worked to develop security access request form using HTML/CSS/JavaScript/jQuery/Bootstrap as a front-end application on top of SharePoint.}$
- Coordinated with management and customer to gather requirements for UI improvements and application functionality.
  - Tracked changes in Jira as features were implemented in the application.
  - Used SharePoint as site asset repository with separate development and stage/demonstrator instances.

#### JR DEVELOPER, APP ENGINEER, NOVA CORPORATION, DISA; FORT MEADE, MD

2016-2019

Assisted in developing in-house RoR application. Administered several COTS applications. Coordinated with database and system administrators and vendors. Applications include internal management tools and CMS for public-facing website.

- Worked to develop calendar module to include in in-house ATO management application built with Ruby on Rails.
- Managed maintenance of COTS applications by receiving advice and patches from application vendors, then planning with, and distributing files to, database administrators to execute patches and upgrades.
- Used development environments for testing and staging upgrades to ensure maximum uptime for production systems.
- Used IIS to manage application configurations, ensure adherence to security requirements, and assist troubleshooting with other agency teams.
  - Ensured application installations meet STIG requirements as needed.
  - Maintained documentation in shared repositories in SharePoint and Subversion.
  - Reviewed BURP scans and implemented improvements to enhance application security.

#### STAFF SERGEANT, UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS; WASHINGTON, DC

2001-2016

Performed musical duties as a member of "The Commandant's Own," U.S. Marine Drum & Bugle Corps. Served additional management and technical roles such as:

- Section Head Managed up to 40 personnel in work-related tasks and personal issues
- Section Leader Directed and instructed up to 10 section personnel in time-based tasks and mentored junior personnel to encourage their success
- Audio Recording Engineer Recorded rehearsals and performances using multi-channel equipment, edited and cataloged recordings, and distributed compilations to unit leadership.

#### Education

#### GENERAL ASSEMBLY, WASHINGTON, DC - WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE

2016

Trained in Full-Stack Web technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, MEAN stack, and many others. Collaborated with classmates and instructors through Github, using Git locally and remotely for version control.

#### UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AT KEARNEY, KEARNEY, NE - B.A. MUSIC

2000

Performed in multiple ensembles and worked as a section leader and as a drill writer for the marching band. Volunteered to assist with open house nights at the campus astronomy observatory.